A Guide to the Virginia Tech Buildings Architectural Collection, 1907-2011 (bulk 1953-1996)
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Virginia Tech Buildings Architectural Collection, 1907-2011 (Bulk, 1953-1996)
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Carneal and Johnston
RG 06/03/02e
19 boxes; 13 oversize folders
Collection consists of architectural drawings, blueprints, and floorplans of selected campus buildings located on the campus of the Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University in Blacksburg, VA.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of architectural drawings, blueprints, and floorplans of selected campus buildings located on the campus of the Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University in Blacksburg, VA. Drawings date from 1907 to 2011, though many are undated. A list of buildings is available in the "Contents List" below.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged in alphabetical order by building name.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
Carneal and Johnston Architectural Drawings, Ms2001-008. Finding aid available online.
Carneal and Johnston Glass Plate Negatives, Ms2014-016
Index terms
Subjects:
Montgomery County (Va.); Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; University History; Blacksburg (Va.); Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University; Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute; University Archives
Genre and Form Terms:
Architectural drawings
Corporate Names:
Carneal and Johnston
- Agnew Hall (Box 1)
- Anaerobic Laboratory, 1965 (Box 18)
- Architecture Annex (Box 1)
- Airport Terminal Facility (Box 1)
- Architecture/Engineering Infill (proposed), 1986 (Box 1)
- Art and Design Learning Center, 1994, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Plans, 1994
  - Plans, 1996
- Airport Area Topography (Box 1)
- Burchard Hall, 1995 (Box 2)
- Cassell Coliseum, 1960 (Box 3)
- Cheatham Hall, 1970 (Box 2, Box 4)
- Cochrane Hall, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
- Cowgill Hall, 1988, 2002-c.2004
  - Renovation, 1988, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Renovations, c.2004? (Box 1, Folder 9, Folder 13)
- Derring Hall, 1966, n.d.
  - Plans, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Alterations (Box 2)
  - Plans (Folder 7)
- Dietrich Hall, 1968 (Box 7)
- Duck Pond/Golf Course Topography (Box 2)
- Field Geology Station Plans (Folder 7)
- First Academic Building, 1953 (Box 18)
- Food Processing and Storage Facility, 1985 (Box 2)
- Graduate Housing (proposed), 1979 (Box 2)
- Hancock Hall, 1986-1987
  - Plans, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Volume 1, 1987 (Box 8)
  - Volume 1a, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Volume 2, 1987 (Box 9)
- Hillcrest Hall (Box 2)
- Hutcheson Hall (Box 2)
- Johnston Student Center, 1988 (Box 11)
- Lane Hall - renovations, 1980 (Box 12)
- Lane Stadium - addition, 1977 (Box 12)
- McBryde Hall, 1969 (Box 12, Box 13)
- Miles Stadium, 1925 (Box 12)
- Off-Campus Student Housing (proposed), 1971 (Box 18)
- Pamplin Hall, 1988 (Box 12)
- Power House, Laundry, Print Shop, 1971-1977 (Box 12)
- Price's Fork Research Station (topography), 1975 (Box 12)
- Price Hall, 1972 (Box 12)
- Payne Hall, 1991 (Box 14)
- Rasche Hall, 1907 (Box 14)
- Randolph Hall, 1972 (Box 14)
- Research and Demonstration Facility, 1989-1992 (Box 14)
  - Plans, 1989
  - Roof Detail, 1991
  - Phase II, 1992
- Sandy Hall, 1981 (Box 15)
- Saunders Hall, 1972 (Box 15)
- Seitz Hall (Box 15)
- Slusher Hall, 1971, 1974 (Box 15)
  - 1971
  - 1974
- Smyth Hall, 1973 (Box 15)
- Squires Hall, 1960 (Box 15)
- Squires Student Center-McBryde Hall Walk (proposed) (Box 15)
- Storage Building, 1934 (Box 18)
- Undergraduate Housing (proposed), 1979 (Box 15)
- University Libraries, 1951-2011, n.d.
  - Carol M. Newman Library, 1951-2011
    - Additions and Renovations, 1951-1994 (Folder 5)
    - Plans, September 1953 (Box 12)
    - Plans, June 7, 1971 (Folder 11)
    - Plans, January 2, 1973 & Revised June 15, 1973 (Folder 12)
    - Plans, January 2, 1973 & Revised March 15, 1978 (Folder 9)
    - Furniture Plans, Additions and Renovations, 1973 (Folder 6)
    - Laminated Plans, Renovation and Addition, 1973 (Folder 8)
    - Proposed renovations, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Proposed renovation, June 1986 (Box 12)
    - Floor plans and proposed renovations (Box 12)
    - Group Study Lounge, Fourth Floor (Folder 3)
    - Lighting Changes (Folder 4)
    - Special Collections Renovations (Box 1, Folder 7, Folder 9, Folder 2)
    - Study Cafe/ Coffee Lounge for First Floor Newman Library (Box 1, Folder 1, Folder 2, Folder 3, Folder 4, Folder 5, Folder 6)
  - Library Storage Facility (Folder 10)
  - Newman Library Plaza (Box 12)
- Utility Building, 1934 (Box 15)
- Veterinary Medicine Clinic (Box 15)
- Virginia Tech Bookstore, 1973 (Box 16)
- Virginia Tech History Musuem (Folder 7)
- Virginia Associated Research Center (VARC), 1964 (Box 18)
  Biographical / Historical
  VARC was an off-campus graduate facility, located in Newport News, Virginia, sponsored by Virginia Tech, the College of William and Mary, and the University of Virginia, in cooperation with the Langley Research Center of NASA. It specialized in applied aerospace research and other basic research in related areas.
- War Memorial Hall - addition, 1972 (Box 17)